Brave young men who rode on the wings of victory.
Memphis Belle is a drama, war, action film directed by Michael Caton-Jones.
The "Memphis Belle" is a World War II bomber, piloted by a
young crew on dangerous bombing raids into Europe.
The crew only have to make one more bombing raid before they
have finished their duty and can go home.
In the briefing before their last flight, the crew
discover that the target for the day is Bremen.
Dennis Dearborn, played by Matthew Modine.
Danny Daly, played by Eric Stoltz.
Luke Sinclair, played by Tate Donovan.
Phil Lowenthal, played by D. B. Sweeney.
Val Kozlowski, played by Billy Zane.
Richard "Rascal" Moore, played by Sean Astin.
Memphis Belle is a 1990 war drama film directed by Michael
Caton-Jones and written by Monte Merrick.
The film stars Matthew Modine, Eric Stoltz, and Harry Connick Jr.
(in his film debut).
Memphis Belle is a fictional version of the 1944 documentary Memphis Belle: A Story of a Flying Fortress by director William Wyler, about the
25th and last mission of an American Boeing B-17 Flying Fortress bomber, the Memphis Belle, based in England during World War II.
The 1990 version was co-produced by David Puttnam and Wyler's
daughter Catherine and dedicated to her father.
The film closes with a dedication to all airmen, friend or foe, who
fought in the skies above Europe during World War II.
The film explores themes of world war ii, bomber, u.s.
air force, danger of life, soldier.
The tone is emotional.